Finding Aid for the Japanese American Research Project Collection about Japanese in the U.S. (Yuji Ichioka papers) LSC.2010.00
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Published Materials
  - Books and other Publications, 4.5 linear ft.
    - Poetry, 364-366
      - TOGAWA Akira [characters]. Shi to zuihitsu sh: Mitsubachi no uta [characters] [Songs of the honeybee: A collection of poems and essays]. Tokyo: Aporon-sha., 1962; (1 item, 433 pp.) (Box 364)
        An anthology primarily of free-form poetry.
      - Totsukuni Tanka-kai [characters]. Kash: Ishokurin [characters] [Transplanted grove: A collection of tanka]. San Francisco: Totsukuni Tanka-kai., 1958; (1 item, 339pp. and 58 pp.) (Box 365)
      - TSUNEISHI Shisei [characters], ed. Hoku-Bei Hototogisu Nysen Kush [characters] [Collection of haiku from North America published in the Hototogisu]. Hollywood: Tachibana Ginsha., 1951; (1 book, 370 pp.) (Box 365)
        An anthology of haiku covering the period from 1916 to 1943.
      - USUDA Yko [characters], ed. USUDA Tenjshi Ikush: Nire no Ochiba [characters] [Fallen elm leaves: Collection of verses left by USUDA Tenjshi]. [Hillsboro:] Privately printed., 1957; (1 item,105 pp.) (Box 366)
      - YASUDA Hakuhanshi [characters], ed. Hoku-Bei Hototogisu Nysen Daini Kush [characters] [Second collection of haiku from North America published in the Hototogisu]. Los Angeles: Tachibana Ginsha., 1958; (1 item, 365 pp.) (Box 365)
        A sequel to Hoku-Bei Hototogisu Nysen Kush above.
      - YASUDA Hakuhanshi. Hoku-Bei Tamamo Nysen Kush [characters] [Collection of haiku from North America published in the Tamamo]. Los Angeles: Tachibana Ginsha., 1959; (1 item, 419 pp.) (Box 365)
        An anthology of haiku published in the Tamamo from May 1948 to May 1958.
      - YASUI Matsuno [characters]. Kash: Yashi no Kage [characters] [The shade of the coconut tree: A collection of tanka]. Hiroshima: Shinjusha., 1951; (1 item, 151 pp.) (Box 364)
      - YASUI Satosuke (Shs) [characters] [characters]. Kash: Ginkens [characters] [Silversword: A collection of tanka]. Nagoya: Tanka Zasshi Hensh-bu., 1950; (1 item, 204 pp.) (Box 366)
        An anthology of 500-odd tanka.
      - YSA Keiz (Hanboku) [characters] [characters]. Hanboku Zensh [characters] [The complete works of Hanboku]. Santa Maria: Privately printed., 1940; (1 item, 532 pp.) (Box 366)
    - Fiction and Literary Essays, 0.5 linear ft.
      - HOZAKA Kamesabur (Kiichi) [characters] [characters]. Wagahai no mitaru Amerika, ka-hen [characters] [America as I saw it. Part II]. Tokyo: Nichi-Bei Shuppan Kykai., 1914; (1 item, 439 pp.) (Box 368)
        A satirical work on the Japanese immigrant society, the Japanese exclusion movement, and United States-Japan relations.
      - NAGAHARA Hideaki (Shson) [characters] [characters]. Yoru ni Nageku [characters] [Lament in the night]. Los Angeles: Sd-sha., 1925; (110pp., 1 item) (Box 368)
        A novel.
      - NAGATA Setsuko [characters] (pseudonym). Matsubazue no Rjin [characters] [characters] [An old man on crutches]. Fukuoka: Yurika Kai., 1949; (111pp., 1 item) (Box 368)
        Essays and verses.
      - NAGATA Setsuko. Wagahai wa inu de aru [characters] [I am a dog]. Fukuoka: Yurika Kai Hon-bu., 1952; (1 item, 276 pp.) (Box 368)
        A novel of a Japanese-American family as seen through the eyes of a dog.
      - SHIMOJIMA Takeo [characters]. Shink Monogatari: Kanashiki ningenfu, zenpen [characters] [A story of faith: A chronicle of a suffering man. Part I]. Tokyo: Shinp-sha., 1938; (1 item, 125 pp.) (Box 368)
        A novel portraying the conversion to Christianity of a young Japanese in California.
      - SUZUKI Kakuichir (Mugen) [characters]. Odorokiitta Bokoku no Shakai [characters] [The wonders of Japanese society]. Tokyo: Nimatsudo., 1923; (1 item, 333 pp.) (Box 368)
        A satire of Japanese society.
      - TANAKA Ryry [characters]. Kurebura no Mura [characters] [Tale of Culebra Village]. Garland: Privately printed., 1965; (1 item, 98 pp.) (Box 368)
        An idealized, fictional account of an agricultural commune which the author tried to start in Colorado.
    - Publications in Japan, 2.5 linear ft.
      regarding the Japanese in America and United States-Japan relations.
      - AOYAGI Ikutar [characters], ed. Zaigai Hjin Dai-Nisei Mondai, Dai-issh [characters] [Problems of the Second Generation Overseas Japanese. Part I]. Tokyo: Imin Mondai Kenky Kai., 1940; (101pp., 1 book) (Box 369)
      - Gaimusho [characters]. Sen-kyhyaku-nij-yon-nen Beikoku Iminh Seitei oyobi kore ni kansuru Nichi-Bei Ksh Keika [characters] [The enactment of the 1924 Immigration Act and the state of Japan-United States negotiations]. Tokyo., (1 book, 229 pp.) (Box 368)
      - Gaimusho. Sen-kyhaku-nij-yon-nen Beikoku Iminh Seitei oyobi kore ni kansuru Nichi-Bei Ksh Keika Kbunsho Eibun Fuzokusho [characters] [The enactment of the 1924 Immigration Act and the state of Japan-United States negotiations: Official documents and related English materials]. Tokyo., (268pp., 1 volume) (Box 368)
      - HAYASHI Tomihei [characters]. Gaikoku Ryoken Kafu oyobi Sash Tetsuzuki: Jkan, Beikoku-hen [characters] [Passport and visa application procedures: Volume I, United States of America]. Tokyo: Kaigai Tsshinsha., 1929; (77pp., 1 item) (Box 370)
      - Imin Mondai Kenky Kai [characters]. Imin Mondai Kenky Kai to Sono Jigy [characters] [The Emigration Problem Research Society and its activities]. Tokyo: Imin Mondai Kenky Kai., 1938; (1 item, 12 pp.) (Box 363)
        A booklet. The Society was founded in 1936 with the support from the Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Japan. In Japanese.
      - Kaigai Nikkeijin Renraku Kykai [characters]. Dai-go-kai Kaigai Nikkeijin Taikai Hkoku-sho [characters] [Report of the 5th Conference of Overseas Japanese]. Tokyo: Kaigai Nikkeijin Renraku Kykai., 1965; (1 item, 88 pp.) (Box 370)
      - Kigen Nisen-roppyaku-nen Hshuku Kaigai Dh Tky Taikai Honbu [characters]. Kigen Nisen-roppyaku-nen Hshuku Kaigai Dh Taikai no Zenb [characters]., 1940; (44 pp.) (Box 362)
        [A comprehensive report on the overseas Japanese Tokyo Conference to commemorate the 2600th anniversary of the birth of Japan]. Tokyo: Kigen Nisenroppyaku-nen Hshuku Kaigai Dh Tokyo Taikai Honbu. The Conference was held in November 1940.
      - MORISHIGE Toshio [characters]. Hiroshima-ken Taizai Bei-Fu Shusseisha Meibo [characters] [Roster of American- and Hawaiian-born Japanese residing in Hiroshima Prefecture]. Hiroshima: Hiroshima-ken Kaigai Kykai., 1939; (1 item, 339 pp.) (Box 362)
        The names of 11,317 American- and Hawaiian-born Japanese staying in Hiroshima Prefecture were listed.
      - NAIT Keiz [characters]. Zaidan Hjin Kaigai Kyiku Kykai Yran [characters] [Association for the Education of Overseas Japanese: An outline]. Kawasaki: Zaidan Hjin Kaigai Kyiku Kykai., 1940; (1 item, 56 pp.) (Box 362)
        A booklet. The Association was founded by Viscount ISHII Kikujir [characters] in 1932.
      - Nihon Bei-Fu Kykai [characters]. Dai-Nisei to Kokuseki Mondai: Dai-Nisei Ssho Dai-san-sh [characters] [The Nisei and the problem of dual-nationality: Nisei Handbook, Series No. 3]. Tokyo: Runbini Shuppan-sha., 1938; (1 item, 58 pp.) (Box 362)
      - Nihon Bei-Fu Kykai. Dai-Nisei to Nihon no Gakk: Dai-Nisei Ssho Dai-rokush [characters] [The Nisei and their education in Japan: Nisei Handbook, Series No. 6]. Tokyo: Runbini Shuppan- sha., 1938; (1 item, 61 pp.) (Box 362)
      - Nihon Bei-Fu Kykai. Nihon Rygaku no Atarashiki Hh: Dai-Nisei Ssho Dai-ky-sh [characters] [A new way to study in Japan: Nisei Handbook, Series No. 9]. Tokyo: Runbini Shuppan-sha., 1938; (1 item, 57 pp.) (Box 362)
      - Nisei Survey Committee. The Nisei: A survey of their life in Japan. Tokyo: Keisen Girls' School., 1939; (1 item, 55 pp.) (Box 362)
        A survey of the educational, vocational, and social problems of 437 Nisei studying in the Tokyo-Yokohama area in 1939.
      - Shakai Seisaku Gakkai [characters] [Society on Social Problems]. Imin Mondai [characters] [Emigration problems]. Tokyo: Dbunkan., 1910; (1 item, 319 pp.) (Box 369)
        The proceedings of the Third Conference of the Shakai Seisaku Gakkai, held on December 19-20, 1909 in Tokyo.
      - YAMADA Fudesabur [characters] Dai-Hiroshima-ken: Skan Dai-jgo-sh-nen G [characters] [Greater Hiroshima Prefecture: Special 15th anniversary issue]. Hiroshima: Hiroshima-ken Kaigai Kykai., 1930; (1 item, 169 pp.) (Box 362)
        The Dai-Hiroshi-ken was published by the Hiroshima-ken Kaigai Kykai [characters] [Hiroshima Prefecture Overseas Association]. The Association was founded in 1915 with a view toward disseminating information and facilitating emigration from Hiroshima Prefecture. The title of the publication was changed from the Hiroshima-ken Naigai Jij [characters] [Domestic and Overseas Affairs of Hiroshima Prefecture] to the Dai-Hiroshima-ken in February 1920.
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1.5 linear ft.
      - KAKAZU, Hashiji K. Destination of Mankind: The world without a boundary. [Kona:] Privately printed., 1966; (1 item, 21 pp.) (Box 363)
      - KOND Chei [characters]. Nihon no Shorai to Minshushugi [characters] [Democracy and the future of Japan]. Tokyo: Kybunkan., 1950; (1 item, 182 pp.) (Box 370)
      - OKAMURA Yoshiyuki [characters]. Sankai no Mado kara [characters] [From the third floor window]. Pasadena: Tkyd., 1929; (257 pp.) (Box 368)
        A collection of miscellaneous newspaper articles which Okamura published in the Rafu Nichibei Shimbun [characters] from 1922 to 1928.
      - SAKAMOTO Tomio [characters]. Hawai Jimbutsu Shin Chizu [characters] [A new Who's Who in Hawaii]. Honolulu: Privately printed., n.d.; (1 item, 129 pp.) (Box 370)
      - SASAKI San'ichir [characters]. Warera wa nani o manabubeki ka [characters] [What should we study?]. New York: Kagaku Shis Fuky Kai., 1923; (1 item, 35 pp.) (Box 363)
        A communist pamphlet.
      - TAKAHARA Yasutami [characters]. Ikkan no Michi [characters] [A consistent philosophy]. Los Angeles: Privately printed., 1920; (1 item, 81 pp.) (Box 363)
        A treatise on Confucianism.
      - TOJI Seiichi [characters]. Nichi-Ei Taish Shiminken Juken Hayawakari [characters] [Lessons [UNK] citizenship in Japanese and English]. Los Angeles: Privately printed., 1951; (1 item, 84 pp.) (Box 363)
      - TSURUTANI Jirokichi [characters]. Fha o koete hachi-j-nen [characters] [Weathering the storm for 80 years]. Kobe: Hygo Kenritsu Awaji Ngy Kt Gakk., 1963; (1 item, 292 pp.) (Box 368)
        Letters sent to students of the Awaji Agricultural High School by an Issei.
      - The Spoilage reviews., 1947 (Box 798, Folder 7)
  - Newspapers, 7.5 linear ft.
    - Town Crier, Los Angeles, and its special publications., 2.5 linear ft.
      - Town Crier, no.1282-2837; no. 2916; 3655-3656; no. 3760; no.3634-4542; nos. 4575-4718. Los Angeles. Daily., January 1, 1950-December 31, 1954; May 1, 1955; December 20-21, 1957; December 28, 1957; January 4-December 16, 1959; January 13-June 2, 1969; (Mimeographed) (Box 348-350, Box 740)
        A one-page news sheet in Japanese, edited and printed by AKAHORI Masaru [characters] in Little Tokyo, Los Angeles. Publication began on July 1, 1946.
    - Amerika Shimbun, San Francisco, 1.0 linear ft.
      - Amerika Shimbun [characters] [The America Shimbun]. Volume 1, no.1-Volume 3, no.82. San Francisco. Weekly., August 3, 1929-May 27, 1939 (Box 743)
        It was edited and published by OKA Shigeki [characters]. Publication was suspended from February 1931 to January 1938, except for one issue. Publication was resumed from Volume 3, no.1 (February 12, 1938), and continued until May 27, 1939 (last issue, Volume 3, no.82). It was then merged with the fu Nipp [characters] [Sacramento Daily News], the Japanese language daily published in Sacramento, California.
        [Box 743 begins with Volume 3, no. 2 (February 18, 1938). Preceding volumes missing. 2/2009]
      - Amerika Shimbun [characters] [America Shimbun]. Volume 3, no.1-2. San Francisco. Irregular., May 29, 1957 & November 12, 1958; (2 issues) (Box 740)
        An attempt to revive the prewar Amerika Shimbun (see Oversize Box 743) by OKA Shigeki.
    - Rare Issues of Vernacular Newspapers, 1.5 linear ft.
      - Beikoku Jitsugy Jih [characters] [The American Industrial Times], no.1. Oakland. Weekly., December 25, 1930; (1 issue) (Box 351)
        This newspaper specialized in agricultural, business, and industrial news.
      - Chuo Jiho [characters] [The Central Times], no.3-4. San Francisco. Weekly., January 1, 1931; January 15, 1931; (2 issues) (Box 351)
      - Gardena no Tomo [characters] [Turf and Garden]. Los Angeles. Monthly., March 1941; September 1941; May 1947; August 1947; December 1965; (5 issues) (Box 351)
        Published by the Nanka Teiengy Remmei [characters] [Southern California Gardeners Federation] which was established in December 1937. Publication was suspended in December 1947, but it was resumed in May 1956.
        no.47 (March 1941)
        no.53 (September 41)
        May 1947
        August 1947
        Volume 10, No. 12 (December 1965)
      - Hokubei Hyron [characters] [North American Review]. Volume 2, no.106; and undated clippings kept by IKEDA Kand [characters], editor. Oakland. Weekly., October 11, 1929; (1 issue and 1 scrapbook) (Box 351)
        It began publication in 1926, and continued until the outbreak of World War II.
      - Hokushin [characters] [The Hoku Shin]. Volume 12, no.4-12; and Volume 14, no.11. San Francisco. Weekly., February 9-April 12, 1924; April 3, 1926; (2 issues) (Box 743)
        The title is also written as [characters]. It began publication in 1913 as the successor to the Kokumin Shimbun [characters], with SOEJIMA Hachir [characters] as its editor. From the April 3, 1926 (Volume 14, no.11) issue, SAWA Eiz [characters] replaced Soejima as its publisher and editor.
      - JACL Reporter. Salt Lake City. Monthly., October 1946; January 1947; (2 issues) (Box 351)
        Published by the National Headquarters of the Japanese American Citizens League. It began publication in 1945, and continued until December 1950.
        vol.1, no.10 (October 1946)
        vol.3, no.1 (January 1947)
      - Kaikysen [characters] [The Class Struggle], no.12. San Francisco. Monthly., May 5, 1927; (1 issue) (Box 351)
        A communist monthly, published by the Zaibei Nihonjin Rd Kykai [characters].
        It began publication in June 1926. From the March 5, 1928 (No. 19) issue, the title was changed to the Zaibei Rd Shimbun [characters] [The Japanese Worker in America] (see Box 351). From the January 10, 1930 (No. 35) issue, it became a semi- monthly under the new title, Rd Shimbun [characters] [The Rodo Shimbun] (see Box 351), the official publication of the Japanese Section of the American Communist Party.
      - Kumiai Jiho [characters] [The Union Times]. Volume 1, no.1-2. San Francisco. Bi-monthly., October 10-December 10, 1931; (2 issues) (Box 351)
        The official publication of the Press Workers Union. The Union was organized in 1931.
      - Kyoyu Jiji [characters] [The Kyoyu Times], no.78 (June 7, 1919), and No. 82 (July 31, 1919). Salt Lake City. Semi-weekly., (2 issues) (Box 351)
        It was published as an official organ by the Rodo Kyoyu Kai [characters] [Japanese Labor Fraternity], an organization established in Salt Lake City in January 1918. It was edited by NISHIMURA Yoshio [characters] (see Box 131).
      - Nichibei Shimbun [characters] [The Japanese American News], no.6672. San Francisco. Daily., June 15, 1918; (1 issue) (Box 351)
      - Nichibei Hyron [characters] [The Japanese American Review], vol. 21, no.439; vol. 27, no.489. Seattle. Monthly., September 30, 1928; February 27, 1935; (2 issues) (Box 351)
        It began publication in 1908. The longest, continuous monthly published in the Pacific Northwest region.
        Volume 21, No. 439 (September 30, 1928)
        Volume 27, No. 489 (February 27, 1935)
      - Nichibei Jidai [characters] [The Nichibei Jidai]. Tokyo. Monthly., September 1954; February 1, 1955; (2 issues) (Box 351)
        First published in 1947. It published articles written by those Issei writers and journalists who returned to Japan before the outbreak of the Pacific War. The publication was later continued as the Nippon to Amerika [characters] [Japan and America].
        vol. 8, no.9 (September 1954)
        vol. 9, no.2 (February 1, 1955)
      - Nichibei Jiji [characters] [The Nichibei Jiji], no.449. Los Angeles. Weekly., October 29, 1931; (1 issue) (Box 351)
        It began publication in 1922
      - Rd [characters] [Labour]. Volume 12, no.167,171; Volume 18, no.298. Seattle. Semi-monthly., March 10, 1932; May 10, 1931; October 10, 1937; (3 issues) (Box 351)
        First published in 1920.
        Volume 12, No. 167 (March 10, 1932)
        Volume 12, No. 171 (May 10, 1931)
        Volume 18, No. 298 (October 10, 1937)
      - Rd no Chikara [characters] [The Workers Power]. Volume 1, no.1. New York. Monthly., June 30, 1923; (1 issue) (Box 351)
        It was published by the Nihonjin Rd Kykai [characters] [Japanese Labour Association] of New York, with NISHIMURA Yoshio (see Box 131) as its editor.
      - Shkan Nichibei [characters] [The Japanese American Weekly]. Volume 1, no.1. San Francisco. Weekly., July 6, 1929; (1 issue) (Box 351)
        Initially, it was started as a weekly supplement to the Nichibei Shimbun [The Japanese American News] (see Box 351) in 1928. Later it became an independent publication.
      - Sk Shh [characters] [The San Francisco Weekly]. San Francisco. Weekly., 1926-1932 (Box 743)
        vol.14, no.38 (October 9, 1926)
        vol.14, no.40 (October 23, 1926)
        vol.14, no.42-45 (November 6-27, 1926)
        vol.15, no.1-3 (January 1-15, 1927)
        vol.17, no.133-134 (August 24 & 31, 1929)
        vol.17, no.137 (September 21, 1929)
        vol.17, no.140 (October 12, 1929)
        vol.18, no.160 (March 15, 1930)
        vol.19, no.220 (May 23, 1931)
        vol.20, no.250 (January 1, 1932)
        Publication began in 1926. A continuation of the Hokushin [The Hoku Shin] (see Oversize Box 743). The Nippon to Amerika, a monthly magazine edited by AZUMI Suimei [characters], is a successor.
      - Taish [characters] [The Taishu]. Seattle. Weekly., October 31, 1940; September 11, 1941 (Box 351)
        A continuation of the Rd [The Labour] (see Box 351) under a new title.
        vol. 21, no.389 (October 31, 1940)
        vol. 22, no.428 (September 11, 1941)
      - Takoma Jiho [characters] [The Tacoma Japanese Times], no.1569. Tacoma. Weekly., April 7, 1932; (1 issue) (Box 351)
        First published in May 1914 with the title, Takoma Shh [characters] [The Tacoma Weekly]. It was changed to the Takoma Jiho in December 1915. It ceased publication in February 1934.
    - Vernacular Press Special Publications, 3.5 linear ft.
      - Hawai Taimusu-sha [characters] [The Hawaii Times]. Hawai Taimusu Skan Rokujusshnen Kineng [characters] [The Hawaii Times 60th Anniversary, 1895-1955]. Honolulu: Hawai Taimusu., (1 volume, varying pagination) (Box 743)
        Included are: reminiscences and biographical sketches of Issei in Hawaii.
      - Hawai Taimusu-sha. Hawai Taimusu Skan Shichijusshnen Kinen-g [characters] [Special 70th Anniversary Edition of the Hawaii Times]. Honolulu., October 2, 1965; (1 item) (Box 352)
        It includes many feature articles on the history of the Japanese in Hawaii.
      - Hawai Taimusu-sha. Hawai Taimusu Skan Shichijusshnen Kinen: Monoshiri Tech [characters] [In commemoration of the 70th anniversary of the Hawaii Times: Fact book]. Honolulu: Hawai Taimusu-sha., 1965; (38pp., 1 item) (Box 352)
      - Hokubei Hchi Shimbun-sha [characters] [The North American Herald]. Hokubei Hchi Nanka Hyaku Jinbutsu [characters] [The North American Herald Southern California Who's Who]. Los Angeles: Hokubei Hchi Shimbun-sha., 1922; (64pp., 1 item) (Box 352)
      - Hokubei Mainichi Shimbun-sha [characters] [The Hokubei Mainichi]. Hokubei Mainichi Shimbun Skan Jusshnen Kineng [characters] [Hokubei Mainichi 10th Anniversary Edition]. San Francisco: Hokubei Mainichi Shimbunsha., 1960; (197pp., 1 item) (Box 352)
      - Jitsugy no Hawai [characters] [The Jitsugy no Hawaii]. Jitsugy no Hawai Skan Sanjusshnen Kineng [characters] [The Jitsugy no Hawaii: 30th Anniversary Edition]. Honolulu: Jitsugy no Hawai., 1941; (237 pp. and 61 pp., 1 item) (Box 357)
        Japanese text 237pp., and English text 61pp. The issue includes articles on the worsening relations between the United States and Japan, and the Japanese community in Hawaii in crisis.
      - Nichibei Jiji-sha [characters] [The Nichi Bei Times]. Imin Kika Kongh Seiritsu Kineng [characters] [Equality in citizenship and naturalization commemoration supplement]. San Francisco: Nichibei Jiji-sha., 1952; (1 item, 96pp. and 6 pp.) (Box 743)
        Special issue to commemorate the passage of the Walter-McCarran Bill.
      - Nichibei Jiji-sha. Kika Tehodoki Shimin Tokuhon [characters] [Citizenship reader: A guide to naturalization]. San Francisco: Nichibei Jiji-sha., 1953; (1 item, 47 pp.) (Box 352)
      - Nichibei Jiji-sha. Nichibei Jiji Jusshnen Kineng [characters] [Special tenth anniversary supplement of the Nichi Bei Times]. San Francisco: Nichibei Jiji-sha., 1956; (1 item, 64pp., and 8 pp.) (Box 744, Folder 6)
      - Shgy Jih-sha [characters] [The Commercial Times]. Skan Nijusshnen Kineng [characters] [Special issue to commemorate the 20th anniversary]. Honolulu: Shgy Jih-sha., 1940; (1 item) (Box 357)
      - Taunkuraiy-sha [characters] [The Town Crier]. Nichi-Bei Shk Hyaku-nensai Gafu [characters] [A photographic album to commemorate 100 years of Japanese-American amity]. Los Angeles: Taunkuraiy-sha., 1960; (144pp., 1 item) (Box 350)
      - Taunkuraiy-sha. Shinneng [characters] [New Year's Edition]. Los Angeles., 1957-1960, 1963-1965; (7 issues) (Box 740)
    - Ofu Nippo or The Sacramento Daily News., 1913 (Box 52)
      Two bound volumes of publications of 1913 of this Japanese language newspaper.
  - Periodicals, 3.0 linear ft.
    - Publications of Literary Groups and Organizations, 3.0 linear ft.
      - Djin Zasshi [characters] [Literary coterie magazines] printed in America. (Box 355-356)
        - Hokubei Senry [characters]. Volume 5, no.12. Seattle. Monthly. Published by the Hokubei Senry Ginsha [characters]., December 1950; (1 issue) (Box 355)
        - Jiry [characters] [Current]. Volume 1, no.5. Los Angeles. Monthly., September 1948; (1 issue) (Box 355)
          Published from April 1948 to July 1950.
        - Kakudo [characters] [Shining Earth]. Volume 1, no.1. Los Angeles., March 1927; (1 issue) (Box 355)
          A magazine of prose and poetry published by the Kakudo-sha [characters] [Kakudo Society] of Los Angeles, a group formed in 1921 to promote the pictorial arts.
        - Kanashiki [characters] [The Anvil], no.1-3. Honolulu. Irregular., February 1947; April 1947; October 1947; (Mimeographed, 3 issues) (Box 356)
          A magazine of essays and poetry.
        - Maguna [characters] [Magna]. Volume 2, no.1. Garfield, Utah. Quarterly., March 1916 (Box 355)
          Publication began in the spring of 1915. A literary journal of poetry, essays, and fiction, published by a group of Japanese working at the Magna Copper Company Refining Plant, Utah.
        - Nanka Bungei [characters] [Southern California Bungei], no.2. Los Angeles. Semi-annual., March 1966; (Mimeographed, 1 issue) (Box 355)
          First published in September 1964.
        - N Y Bungei NY [characters] [The New York Bungei], no.7. New York City. Annual., December 1961; (1 issue) (Box 355)
          A magazine of fiction, essays, and some poetry, published by the literary group, New York Bungei, since 1955. It is edited by AKIYA Ichir [characters].